const quizData = [
  {
    question: " Q1. The default link color for hyperlinks? ",
    a: "green",
    b: "yellow",
    c: "blue",
    d: "red",
    ans: "ans-3",
  },
  {
    question: " Q2. What is the full form of HTML ",
    a: "Hypertext Markup Language",
    b: "Hypermedia Markup Language",
    c: "Hyper makrup language",
    d: "none of above",
    ans: "ans-1",
  },

  {
    question: "Q3. What is the full form of JS",
    a: "JavaScript",
    b: "Java speech",
    c: "Java language",
    d: "none of above",
    ans: "ans-1",
  },

  {
    question: "Q4. What is the full form of CSS",
    a: "Cascading Speed Sheet",
    b: "Cascading Style Sheet",
    c: "Colourful style sheet",
    d: "none of above",
    ans: "ans-2",
  },

  {
    question: "Q5. Which tag is used to underline text",
    a: "<a>",
    b: "<hr>",
    c: "<br>",
    d: "<u>",
    ans: "ans-4",
  },

  {
    question: "Q6. To make a comment in HTML you use ",
    a: "<!-- -->",
    b: "//",
    c: "/* ",
    d: "#",
    ans: "ans-1",
  },

  {
    question: "Q7. CSS to make text of all <p> tags red",
    a: "p{colour:red}",
    b: "p-style{color:red}",
    c: "p{color:red}",
    d: "p{color style :red}",
    ans: "ans-3",
  },

  {
    question: "Q8. JavaScript files have the file extention ",
    a: ".java",
    b: ".css",
    c: ".html",
    d: ".js",
    ans: "ans-4",
  },

  {
    question: "Q9. Choose the correct HTML element for largest heading",
    a: "<h1>",
    b: "<head>",
    c: "<h6>",
    d: "<heading>",
    ans: "ans-1",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Q10. What is the correct HTML element for inserting a line break ",
    a: "<break>",
    b: "<hr>",
    c: "<lb>",
    d: "<br>",
    ans: "ans-4",
  },
];

const question = document.querySelector(".question");
const option1 = document.querySelector("#option-1");
const option2 = document.querySelector("#option-2");
const option3 = document.querySelector("#option-3");
const option4 = document.querySelector("#option-4");
const submit = document.querySelector("#submit");
const answers = document.querySelectorAll(".answer");
const showScore=document.querySelector("#showScore");

let questionCount = 0;

let score = 0;

const loadQuestion = () => {
  const questionList = quizData[questionCount];

  question.innerText = questionList.question;
  option1.innerText = questionList.a;
  option2.innerText = questionList.b;
  option3.innerText = questionList.c;
  option4.innerText = questionList.d;

  
};
loadQuestion();

function getanswer() {
  let answer;
  answers.forEach((currAns) => {
    if (currAns.checked) {
      answer = currAns.id;
    }
  });
  return answer;
}
 const deselectAll=()=>{
    answers.forEach((curAnsElem)=> curAnsElem.checked=false);
 }

submit.addEventListener("click", () => {
  const checkedAnswer = getanswer();
  console.log(checkedAnswer);

  if (checkedAnswer === quizData[questionCount].ans) {
    score++;  
  } 

  deselectAll();
  questionCount++;
  if (questionCount < quizData.length) {
    loadQuestion();
    
  }
  else{
    
    showScore.innerHTML=`<h1> You scored ${score}/${quizData.length}üëç </h1>
    <button class="btn" onClick="location.reload()">Try Again</button>`;
    showScore.classList.remove('scoreArea'); 
    submit.style.display='none'; 
}

  
});
